# DANCHO JOSIFOV

# Senior UI/UX Designer

UI/UX designer with experience creating, delivering, and supervising digital projects such as mobile apps, websites, and cloud platforms. An experienced, analytical, creative, problem solver and results-driven designer with a creative eye and strong knowledge in UI/UX, user-centered design, and design thinking.

#### CONTACT

#### Phone

+38976377177

#### **Email**

danejosifov@gmail.com

#### Linkedin

linkedin.com/in/dane-josifov

# **LANGUAGE**

# English

Professional working proficiency

# Macedonian

Native proficiency

# German

Elementary proficiency

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**



#### Adeva, Skopje

2019 - present

#### Senior UI/UX Designer

- Worked with the internal product team to completely rebrand Adeva's identity, to better match their mission and vision.
- Worked closely with the development team to ensure pixel-perfect implementation.
- Built wireframes and interactive prototypes to evaluate flows.
- Worked with the community manager to produce marketing assets.
- Improved monthly page views (+100%) and reduced the bounce rate (-20%) as a result of the design work.

**Technologies:** MailChimp, Google Analytics, Photoshop, Adobe XD, Figma, Illustrator, Canva, Adobe InDesign



#### EXTFOX, Kavadarci

2017 - 2019

#### UX / UI Designer, Graphic designer

- Worked directly with the CEO and led the design of a digital ad service.
- Responsible for the whole design process: from early product development/roadmap, through all stages of design to product launch, leading to a new revenue stream for the company.
- Designed and prototyped a social network named "Guidance Guide" with over 5000 product reviews and guides, aimed for parents.
- Designed and animated over 300 Google Ads compliant banners.
- Acted as the steward of the brand and ensured nothing damages it.
- Brought the company up to speed with today's design standards leveraging modern design methodologies and practices in user experience and interface design as well as research.

**Technologies:** Firebase, Photoshop, Sketch, Adobe XD, Illustrator, Adobe Animate, SocialEngine

#### Freelance

2015 - present

#### **UX / UI Designer, Graphic designer**

- Created the branding, positioning, and visual communication for a yearly outdoor cycling festival, with over 6000 yearly visitors.
- Helped craft and elevate digital products and have brought ideas into reality with a smart, well-designed, human-centered process.
- Provided guidance and consultation to various companies and entrepreneurs to elevate UX, UI, and product design using best practices and design thinking methodology.
- Designed hundreds of social media ads for global companies.

# COURSES

# Microsoft 2016

Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3

Course number 20480

Microsoft

2016

Developing ASP.NET MVC 4 Web Applications

Course number 20486

Microsoft

2016

Developing Windows Azure and Web Services

Course number 20487

# **EDUCATION**

Ss. Cyril and Methodius University - Faculty of Mechanical Engineering Sep. 2010 - Jun. 2016

Master degree

Master of Science in Industrial Design and Marketing

University "Goce Delcev" -Faculty of Natural and

Technical Sciences Sep. 2007 – Sep. 2010 Bachelor's Degree

Baccalaureus, NQF VI B, Computer Design Engineering

# SKILLS

**Expertise** Product Design, Web Design, UX prototyping, Wireframing, UI Design, Branding

Tools AdobeXD, Figma, Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Adobe Animate, Sketch

Languages HTML5, CSS3